Guide to the Department of International Relations, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of International Relations, Yale University, records
1926-1967
RU 593
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.25
(6 boxes)
The records consist of office files and student records documenting the operations and activities of the Yale Department of International Relations.
Yale University. Dept. of International Relations
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of office files and student records documenting the operations and activities of the Yale Department of International Relations.
Arrangement
The records are arranged as follows: I. Student Records, 1926-1951. II. Administrative Records, 1934-1967.
International relations -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Students; Yale University. Dept. of International Relations
- Records, 1926-1967; Accession 1968-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  Student records restricted 75 years from date individual left Yale.
  - Student records, 1926-1951
    - Boessneck, F.O., 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Brown, J.S., 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Campbell, Ford, 1933-1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Chapman, M.K., 1929-1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Cohen, Myer, 1933-1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Davis, G.T., 1930-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Efron, A., 1937-1939 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Gordman, H.S., 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Hill, P.C., 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Jackson, W.E., 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Kreye, G.W., 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Marshall, R.L., 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Millikan, G.L., 1935-1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Muther, E.F., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Parks, W.J., 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Rollins, A.A., 1926-1936 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Seidman, H., 1934-1937 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Winterbotham, G.S., 1935 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Witman, S.L., 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Yarrow, C.H., 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Young, G.K., 1934-1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Class of 1940 course cards, 1936-1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Class of 1941 information, 1939-1941 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Class of 1941 course cards, 1937-1941 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Class of 1942 information, 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Class of 1942 course cards, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Students, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Class of 1943 information, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Class of 1943 course cards, 1939-1943 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Class of 1944 information, 1942-1944 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Class of 1944 course cards, 1940-1944 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Class of 1945 course cards, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Classes of 1945W, 1945W0, 1945WF course cards, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Class of 1946 course cards, 1942-1946 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Class of 1946M course cards, 1941-1946 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Class of 1946N course cards, 1938-1946 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Class of 1947M course cards, 1942-1948 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Class of 1947N course cards, 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Class of 1947 course cards, 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Class of 1948 course cards, 1941-1948 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Class of 1949M course cards, 1942-1949 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Class of 1949 course cards, 1942-1949 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Class of 1950F course cards, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Class of 1950 course cards, 1945-1950 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Class of 1951 course cards, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Administrative Records, 1934-1967
    - Department Statistics, 1934-1945 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - IR Degrees Granted and Dissertation Titles, 1935-1954 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - New Department Students, 1939-1960 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Courses in diplomacy, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Dissertations: proposed topics, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Dissertations: Hoor, Dr. E., "Austria", 1950 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Dissertations: Brecher, Michael "The Kashmir Impasse", 1951 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Fellowships and Scholarships, 1949-1953 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Degree Requirements - Inquires, 1953-1956 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Fellowships - Scholarships: Awards, Analysis, Inquiries, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Fellowships - Scholarships: Awards, Analysis, Inquiries, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Fellowships-Scholarships: Awards, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Dissertation Lists and Prospectuses, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Fellowships-Scholarships: Awards and Applications, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Department Correspondence and Memoranda, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Fellowships: Applications, Awards, 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Fellowships: Applications, Awards, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Fellowship Applications (Students in residence), 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - New IR Program, 1961-1961 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Fellowships-Scholarships: Awards, Analysis, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Fellowships (Admissions), 1963 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    - Proposal of a Revised Program in IR, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    - IR Admissions and Grants, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    - Admission Inquiries, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - Fellowships (Admissions), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 70)
    - Summer Aid, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 71)
    - Admission Inquiries, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 72)
    - Fellowships and Admissions, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 73)
    - Admission Inquiries, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - I R Students Mid-Year Evaluations, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - IR Admissions and Grants, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 76)
    - New Students, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 77)
    - IR Admissions and Awards, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 78)